

SAAD BARADAN

720-341-9511

FRONT END ENGINEER



https://www.linkedin.com/in/saad-baradan



Portfolio Website

SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML/CSS
- Sass
- React/Redux
- React Native
- Vue.is
- StencilJS
- Electron
- jQuery
- Jest/Enzyme
- Cypress
- Playwright

Tools/Processes

- Scrum/Kanban
- Git
- Bitbucket
- Jira
- ClickUp
- Linux
- CircleCI
- Postman
- Figma

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software & Design, Front End Engineering
Jan 2019 - Aug 2019

Colorado State University,

M.A. Philosophy

Sept 2013 - May 2015

University of Colorado Denver, B.A. Philosophy

June 2007 - May 2011

SUMMARY

With over 4 years of experience, I have built a variety of web client and desktop applications in the geo-spatial, healthcare, and AI tech spaces. I have extensive experience working on cross-functional teams of project managers, engineers, and designers to deliver the best user experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer, Imaige

November 2023 - Present (Contract)

- Lead Frontend development of Imaige AI's desktop & web client applications using TypeScript, React, & Electron
- Utilize TypeScript & StencilJS to build Google Chrome extensions
- Configure, sign, and publish Mac and Windows client desktop builds for bi-weekly production releases
- Use Bitbucket & YAML to build & manage Frontend build pipelines
- Collaborate with a cross-functional team of QA, Backend, and AI engineers on a daily basis
- Work with designers to review and implement Figma designs
- Mentor Junior engineers by onboarding them and doing weekly paired programming sessions
- Use Jira to manage and resolve new feature and bug tickets in a timely manner

Software Engineer - Frontend, Loyal Health

Jan 2022 - Oct 2023

- Utilize TypeScript & React to build and maintain a web client data management application
- Use Storybook to build a library of reusable UI components
- Communicate & collaborate with cross-functional teams of engineers, designers, and product managers on a daily basis
- Deploy modern, performant, and maintainable code to production on a weekly basis
- Collaborate with Backend engineers to analyze, troubleshoot, and consume RESTful APIs
- Work with designers to review and implement Figma designs
- Use Cypress & Playwright to build out integration and unit tests
- Develop a curriculum for summer interns and provide mentorship throughly weekly check-ins and pair programming sessions
- Lead team to being 1st to accomplish various tech debt initiatives

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Delivery Software Engineer, IQGeo

Jan 2020 - Jan 2022

- Utilize Vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, & React to build out new features and fix bugs
- Use Python, Psycopg2, & PostgreSQL to build and enhance RESTful APIs
- Use Linux to develop, test, and deploy software to various environments
- · Work directly with clients to design, build, test, and deploy new features
- Manage and multi-task between 2-3 projects and client stakeholders at one time
- Implement various geospatial libraries like OpenLayers, Leaflet, & Turf.js
- Implement new installs of IQGeo products for clients
- Collaborate remotely with colleagues across US and international time zones

Instructor of Philosophy, Southern New Hampshire University

Jun 2023 - Present, (Part-time)

- Teaching the following online courses:
 - Ethics in Global Society (PHI 218)
 - Ethical Decision-Making & Problem-Solving (PHI 260)
- Utilize academic CRMs such as Desire2Learn & BrightSpace
- Build course content including announcements, diagrams, and video lectures
- Engage in continuing education seminars and trainings
- Host office hours and tutoring sessions through Zoom
- Provide course construction feedback and improvements

Instructor of Philosophy, Colorado Community College System

Jun 2017 - Aug 2023, (Part-time)

- Teaching the following courses:
 - Intro to Logic (PHI 1013)
 - Intro to Ethics (PHI 1012)
 - Intro to Philosophy (PHI 1011)
 - Environmental Ethics (PHI 2018)
 - Business Ethics (PHI 2005)
- Build course content including exercise sets, quizzes, essay assignments, syllabus, and discussions
- Utilize academic CRMs such as Desire2Learn & Blackboard Online
- Engaging in CCCS's Course Development & Feedback Program